* More

* More

Type your search and hit enter

* Hot Topics

Privacy Policy
==============

Welcome
-------

We’re glad you chose to visit an IDG Communications, Inc. (“IDGC”) site! We care about your privacy and the information you share with us and want you to understand how we are using and protecting the information we collect about you. IDGC is respectful of data privacy and adopts best practice in compliance with applicable privacy law and regulations, including the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”).

Use of this website
-------------------

This privacy policy describes the information we collect from you and how it may be stored and processed in the United States of America and across the IDG Communications Publishing Network as described below.

This website, and associated IDGC events and publications provide products, content, and services for a professional and consumer audience and is not intended for individuals under the age of 13 years old. We do not knowingly collect or store personal data provided by anyone under 13 years of age.

_If you are a European Union (EU) resident, please note that there are a number of provisions in this privacy policy that apply uniquely to you._

_If you are a California (US) consumer, please note there are a number of provisions in this privacy policy that also apply uniquely to you._

This Document Describes
-----------------------

What information we collect
---------------------------

IDGC collects data about you that is limited to the kind of information that can be found on a typical business card: first name, last name, job title, employer/company name, work address, work email, and work phone number. In some cases, we may ask you to provide additional professional information such as the size of the company you work for, and industry type.

When you use our website, we share information that we collect from you, such as your email (in hashed form), with our identity partner/service provider, acting as joint controllers. This is [LiveRamp](https://liveramp.com/privacy/). This partner return’s an online identification code – which contains pseudonomized data (not directly identifiable) and will not be used by LiveRamp to re-identify you – that we may store in our first-party cookie for our use in online, in-app, and cross-channel advertising and it may be shared with advertising companies to enable interest-based and targeted advertising. You may opt out at any time to LiveRamp’s processing here: [https://liveramp.com/opt\_out/](https://liveramp.com/opt_out/)  

For visitors from the EU/EEA/UK/CH you will be asked for your consent when you visit our sites through our Consent Management Platform.

For Californian visitors you may opt-out by following the “Do not share my personal data” link in the footer of our sites.

To enhance and/or update the information that you have provided to us, we may combine it with professional information or personal data that we collect from third party sources. The personal data that we refer to in this document is the personal and professional information you provide, as well as information that we obtain from third party sources, both of which we typically combine as one user record.

This site also collects and stores certain information automatically using cookies and similar technologies, including IP addresses, the region or general location of a computer or device accessing the internet, browser type, operating system, page view history, and other usage information. See our [Cookie](https://www.pcworld.com/about/cookie-policy) [Policy](https://www.pcworld.com/cookie-policy) for further details or if you are an EU resident or California consumer, visit our [Member Preferences Center](https://www.pcworld.com/about/member-preferences) to modify your cookie settings.

_However, to the extent that any cookie can uniquely identify a computer, mobile device, or tablet (“Device”), or the person using that Device, and you are an EU resident, under the GDPR, this is personal data. Therefore, this privacy policy shall apply to such personal data collected by IDGC._

_Similarly, if you are a California consumer, under the CCPA, to the extent that any cookie can uniquely identify you or the device you, or any other person is using, via an IP address or other online identifier, this is also personal data._

How we collect it
-----------------

We may collect your personal data when you register to receive any of the products, content or services offered by IDGC or its third party sponsors (“sponsors”) such as publications, subscriptions, contests, newsletters, memberships, premium content, webcasts, video, white papers, online seminars, conferences and events.

#### What happens if you don’t provide personal data?

In order for us to provide the products, content or services you request, we need your personal data. Therefore, if you do not provide such personal data, we cannot deliver the products, content or services.

#### IDG Communications Publishing Network

This website is one of many that IDGC and its group of undertakings operates, all of which we collectively refer to as the IDG Communications Publishing Network. Where permitted by law, we may share the personal data we collect about you with another IDG Communications Publishing Network company so that we can provide you with information about products, content and services that might interest you, and for internal analytical and business development purposes. [Please click here for a list](https://foundryco.com/idgnet/) of the online and print publications included in the IDG Communications Publishing Network.

How do we safeguard your personal data?
---------------------------------------

#### Security of your personal data

IDGC maintains safeguards which include technical and organizational security measures to protect your personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorized use, access, inadvertent disclosure, alteration, and destruction, and we require the third parties we contract with to support IDGC’s business operations to employ reasonable security measures as well (see “When and how we share your information with others” below).

We update and test security on an ongoing basis and restrict access to your personal data to only those who need to know in order to provide IDGC’s products, content or services to you.

#### Storage of your personal data

We may store your personal data using IDGC’s own secure on-site servers or other internally hosted technology. Your personal data may also be stored by third parties, via cloud services or other technology, to whom IDGC has contracted with, to support IDGC’s business operations (see “When and how we share your information with others” below).

These third parties do not use or have access to your personal data other than for cloud storage and retrieval, and IDGC requires such parties to employ at least the same level of security that we use to protect your personal data (see “Security of your personal data” above).

What we do with the personal data we collect
--------------------------------------------

We use the personal data that we collect to communicate with you, deliver what you request, improve our service, and to present other information and business offers that may be of interest.

#### To communicate with you

We may use your personal data to send you important notices, such as communications about your registration, transactions, and changes to IDGC’s terms, conditions, policies, and/or other internal purposes.

#### To deliver what you request

We may use your personal data to provide the products, content or services you request. If you enter a sweepstake, contest, or similar IDGC promotion, we may use your personal data to administer such promotion.

#### To improve our service

We may use your personal data for auditing, data analysis, and research to improve IDGC’s products, content and services.

#### To present offers that may be of interest to you

We may contact you to offer you additional IDGC or third party products, content or services that may be of interest to you. When we contact you regarding any such business offers, your personal data continues to be held by IDGC, unless you specifically indicate that IDGC can share it, such as when you tell us you wish to receive a business offer from one of our third party sponsors.

The legal basis we have for processing your personal data
---------------------------------------------------------

_The GDPR requires data collectors, such as IDGC, to have a legal basis to use the personal data of EU residents. Therefore, this section shall apply to any such personal data collected by IDGC._

IDGC uses the personal data that you provide to supply you with high-quality products, content and services as you request, to send important notices, and for internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, and research to provide you with the information you need to make the most informed technology purchasing decisions.

We may also use your personal data to offer you products, content or services that may be of interest to you, based upon your interests or the preferences you shared with us, and may share your personal data with third party sponsors of content, events, and other business services or offers.

The legal basis for processing your personal data is your consent. In certain circumstances we may otherwise process your personal data if IDGC has a legitimate interest in doing so and IDGC is not infringing any of your rights and freedoms.

When IDGC processes your personal data for IDGC’s legitimate interests, IDGC will consider and balance any potential impact on you and your rights under data protection and any other relevant law. Our legitimate business interests do not override your interests. IDGC will not use your personal data in circumstances where your rights and freedoms override our legitimate interests, unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law.

When and how we share your personal data with others
----------------------------------------------------

IDGC may share your personal data to deliver content and services from our sites, affiliated companies and third parties services that might interest you, including sponsored content and events, for business operations, and to comply with valid legal processes.

_If you are an EU resident, IDGC will only share your personal data with third parties outside of the IDG Communications Publishing Network, with your consent._

#### For content and services that may interest you or that you request

As we mention above, your personal data may be shared within the IDG Communications Publishing Network to provide you with information about products, content and services that might interest you and for internal analytical and business development purposes (see “IDG Communications Publishing Network” above). We may also share your personal data with third parties to deliver third party sponsored content or other services that you request (see “third party sponsored content and events” below). As indicated above (see “To present offers that may be of interest to you”), however, your personal data continues to be held by IDGC, unless you specifically indicate that IDGC can share it with the third party sponsor.

#### For business operations

We may also share your personal data with third parties we have contracted with to support IDGC’s business operations including delivery, fulfillment, payment processing, email deployment, suppression list management and data processing.

#### For third party sponsored content and events

IDGC partners with third party sponsors to make available a large library of content to our users, such as white papers, professional events (live or online), as well as other business services or offers. In return for access to such offers, we may ask you to provide us with personal data as part of the registration.

We may use your personal data to send you the business offer you request. In addition, your personal data may be shared with the third party sponsor(s) of the offer to communicate with you regarding the offer. Please note that once your personal data is shared with the sponsor, the sponsor’s privacy policy, including information on how to opt-out in the future, will apply to your personal data.

#### As required by law

Your personal data may be shared when authorized by law or necessary to comply with a valid legal process.

#### In the event of new ownership

If part or all the ownership of IDGC or any of its products or services are sold or transferred, your personal data will be transferred to the new owner.

#### International Data Transfers

_This section shall apply to any personal data collected by IDGC from EU residents._

If IDGC shares your personal data within the IDG Communications Publishing Network or with any other third party as described in this privacy policy and your personal data will be transferred to a State which is not a Member State of either the European Union or the EEA, or deemed adequate by the European Commission, IDGC (as a data controller/data exporter) will only conduct such transfer (to a data processor/data importer) if there are suitable safeguards in place, such as binding corporate rules, standard contractual clauses, approved Codes of Conduct, or approved certification mechanism. For more information, please contact IDGC’s Data Protection Officer (See contact details below).

How long we keep your personal data
-----------------------------------

We retain your personal data for the duration of your business relationship with us, and we hold your information only as long as necessary for each purpose we use it, unless we have obtained your consent to use for another or similar purpose.

Your rights and preferences
---------------------------

If you inform us that you want IDGC to provide the categories and specific pieces of personal data IDGC collects, your personal data erased (if you are an EU resident) or deleted (if you are a California consumer), that you do not want your personal data sold (if you are a California consumer), that you no longer wish for us to communicate with you for marketing purposes, or to otherwise restrict IDGC’s processing of your personal data, we may retain some basic information in order to avoid sending you unwanted materials in the future, and to keep a record of your request and our response.

#### Confirming your personal data

_This section shall apply to any personal data collected by IDGC from EU residents and California consumers._

To confirm that IDGC is processing your personal data, or to access, update or correct the personal data IDGC holds about you, or to obtain a copy to reuse for your own purposes, please send an email to: [DataRequest@idg.com](mailto:DataRequest@idg.com) (or the mailing address below).

The categories of personal data IDGC has collected about consumers, the categories of sources from which personal data is collected, the business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling (if applicable) personal data, the categories of third parties with whom IDGC shares personal data, and the specific pieces of personal data IDGC has collected about consumers, can be generally be found in this privacy policy.

If, however, you require additional information and/or to otherwise exercise your rights under the CCPA to request the categories and specific pieces of personal data IDGC collects, please send an email to: [DataRequest@idg.com](mailto:DataRequest@idg.com?subject=CCPA%20Request) (or the mailing address below) and please put CCPA Request in the subject line.

#### Erasing or deleting your personal data

_This section shall apply to any personal data collected by IDGC from EU residents or California consumers._

If you want your personal data erased and you are an EU resident, please send an email to: [preferences@idg.com](mailto:preferences@idg.com) (or the mailing address below).

If you are a California consumer, and you want your personal data deleted, please send an email to: [preferences@idg.com](mailto:preferences@idg.com?subject=CCPA%20Request) (or the mailing address below) and please put CCPA Request in the subject line.

#### To opt-out of marketing communications

If you want IDGC to stop communicating with you for marketing purposes, please visit our [Member Preferences Center](https://www.pcworld.com/about/member-preferences).

#### To restrict processing of your personal data

If you want to otherwise restrict IDGC’s processing of your personal data, please send an email to: [websites@idg.com](mailto:websites@idg.com) (or the mailing address below).

#### Opt out of the sale of your personal data

California consumers can exercise their rights to opt out of the selling of their personal data (as applicable) under the CCPA, as described in Your California Privacy Rights below.

Your California Privacy Rights
------------------------------

Throughout this privacy policy, we have explained how your unique rights as a California consumer apply. For a complete statement of these rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA), including the right to opt out of the selling of your personal data and how you can exercise them please visit [Your California Privacy Rights](https://www.pcworld.com/about/ccpa).

How can we help? Getting in touch
---------------------------------

#### Questions, concerns or complaints:

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about IDGC’s personal data practices or this privacy policy, we encourage you to get in touch with our Data Protection Officer.

If you believe you have suffered harm due to a breach of your rights by IDGC under this privacy policy, and IDGC has not handled your complaint in a reasonably sufficient manner, any EU resident may also file a complaint with the applicable supervisory authority.

The contact information for IDGC’s Data Protection Officer is:

Shane Lyster  
c/o IDG Direct  
Millennium House  
Great Strand Street  
Dublin 1  
Ireland  

IDGC has also designated a Representative _in the EU_:  
IDG Communications Media AG  
Lyonel-Feininger-Strasse 26  
Munich 80807  
Germany  

#### Mailing address

Should you choose to notify us of any of the above preferences by postal service, here is our address:

IDG Communications, Inc.  
c/o Member Services  
140 Kendrick Street, Building B  
Needham, MA 02494  
U.S.A.  
Last updated: 22 February 2022 \[Version PP-201219001\]

PCWorld helps you navigate the PC ecosystem to find the products you want and the advice you need to get the job done.

* Policies

* About

* PCWorld Categories

* Subscribe
    * 

Explore the Foundry Network + Tech AdvisorTechHiveMacworld

Top Of Page

Do Not Sell My Info

Privacy Settings
